

PROFILE

For the past three years, I have been professionally developing software applications, web pages, and server scripts. For the ten plus years prior to that I have been developing algorithms to control and connect to various types of Robotic equipment, including: Robots, vision systems, VDF controller, PLCs, Lasers, etc.



(920)602-1140



gensy83@gmail.com



github.com/GensCodeB0t

linkedin.com/in/ryan-gens-133b9154



EDUCATION

COMPUTER SCIENCE / BACHELORS

LAKELAND UNIVERSITY / 2014 -2018

Notable classes include: Java EE, Visual C#, C++, Android, Operating

Systems, Data Warehousing and Data Mining

NOTE: Transcripts are available upon request



ELECTRICAL MECHANICAL TECHNOLOGY / ASSOCIATES

MORAINE PARK TECHNICAL COLLEGE / 2005 - 2007

This program focused on the design and creation of industrial systems. Notable classes include: Industrial Visual Basic, PLC programming, Digital

Graduated with High Honors.

ELECTRICAL APPRENTICE / DIPLOMA

MORAINE PARK TECHNICAL COLLEGE / 2002 – 2003

Pre-Apprenticeship program that focused on the concepts of electricity. Notable classes include: Industrial wiring and PLC programming

EXPERIENCE -

OWNER / SOFTWARE DEVELOPER / AUTOMATION ENGINEER

GADGET DEVELOPMENT STUDIOS // current

Software / industrial automation consulting firm specializing in SCADA, robotics, PLC, application, and website/mobile development



SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INSTRUCTOR

MORAINE PARK TECHNICAL COLLEGE // current

The Software Development details can be found here:

https://www.morainepark.edu/programs/information+technology+-+software+developer/

Next year I will begin teaching Python as a core language for the program



YB.NET

JAVA

C#

SQL

HTML

JAVASCRIPT

AWARDS

GRADUATED SUMMA
CUM LAUDE WITH A 4.0
GRADE POINT AVERAGE
Lakeland University // 2018

LEAD PROGRAMER
INITEGRATED MFG
Moraine Park Technical College
// 2007

TECHNICAL ACHIEVEMENT AWARD Moraine Park Technical College // 2003

EXPERIENCE -

(continued)

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

ALTERNATIVE SOLUTIONS INC // 2016 - 2018

Software development consulting firm.

- Notable projects include: Multi-threaded, xml deserialization program used to convert data from a legacy system to a Flat file used as input to a new system. This project includes a OLEDB connection to conversion lookup tables.
- Dynamic Web site upgrade using J2EE running on an Apache Tomcat webserver. This project was developed using JAVA, HTML, JQUERY, JAVASCRIPT, and Velocity.
- SSIS insurance bureau reporting project. This project required a multithreaded VB.NET/C# GUI to trigger as SSIS package that pulled data from a Data Warehouse and MOLAP cube into a Flat file for use by a bureau system.

SENIOR AUTOMATION TECHNICIAN / BI ANALYST / IT ANALYST

AMERICAN ORTHODONTICS // 2008 - 2016

Orthodontics manufacturing company.

BI related duties include: NAV maintenance, ShopVue maintenance, modification and maintenance to SQL tables, Server Scripting (PowerShell), and SCADA/ Web Development

Automation related duties include: SCADA/ Web Development, mentoring junior technicians, PLC programming, Robotics programming, troubleshooting, machine design.

Notable Projects:

- Web based SCADA development. This project featured a LABVIEW backend with a web page front-end and a SQL server 2012 database. The Web front-end was created using the Twitter Bootstrap to provide a responsive site, along with the Google Graphs API for reporting.
- Serial to Ethernet data parsing program. This project scanned the USB ports of a desktop computer for connected devices and allowed the use to select which port the desired device was connected to (including comm. settings such as baud rate, parity, etc.). The port was then monitor for incoming data, displayed that data to the user and relayed it to an Ethernet base camera. The program also monitored a port for a high signal that switched an opto-coupler, which triggered a KVM switch.
- Power shell barcode interpreter. This project hooked the keyboard buffer of a desktop computer, and monitored it for a specific combination of key strokes. Once it is determined that the input is from a barcode scanner, the program reads the input from a product code, which is referenced against an EXCEL table, for file path. The file the path points to is then opened.



REFERENCES -



Dave Tullberg

MAINTENANCE MANAGER AT AMERICAN ORTHODONTICS

(920)912-8657



Denise Bohlman

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT ALTERNATIVE SOLUTIONS INC

(920)207-6437



Gerry Puls

MAINTENANCE TECHNICIAN AT AMERICAN ORTHODONTICS

(920)287-6365



Reed Gauthier

AUTOMATION TECHNICIAN AT AMERICAN ORTHODONTICS

(920)860-0901